TAKAHIRO ODA

tak0812hir[at]gmail.com https://taka-oda.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research lies at combining of artificial intelligence and machine learning with social science and philosophy to create a combination that can be integrated into policy and business in order to design an unforeseen version of society. Especially I am interested in applying counterfactual policy evaluation and data-driven mechanism design to public issues, using human behavioral data obtained from interactive systems.

My work is situated at the intersection of computing, communities, and constructionism.

EDUCATION

California Institute of Technology

Pasadena, CA

Ph.D. Student in Computer Science.

expected from September 2022

Research Field: Economics and Computation, Machine Learning, History

Keio University

Tokyo, Japan

Bachelor of Economics. April 2018 – March 2022

EXPERIENCE

Squirrel AI Learning by Yixue Group

Shanghai, China

Research Partner (under an outsourcing agreement)

April 2020 – *November* 2021

Work on the research and practice of data-driven STEM education.

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Research Experience for Undergraduates

February 2020 – November 2021

Research on sourcing student open-ended solutions to create scalable learning opportunities under a supervision of Prof. Kenneth R. Koedinger.

atama plus, Inc.

Tokyo, Japan

Research and Development Intern

June 2019 – Present

Work on development and implementation of AI-based educational applications.

INVOLVED PROJECTS

Policy Garage –is a Japanese NPO that accelerates independent projects for open innovation in public policies of Japanese local governments. A regular technical contributor and advisor since March 2021.

Open Bandit Project —is an open-source research project that aims to enable realistic and reproducible experiments on bandit algorithms and their off-policy evaluation. The project consists of a large-scale real-world dataset called Open Bandit Dataset and Python software called Open Bandit Pipeline. Awarded: **The Prime Minister's Award for Open Innovation** by the Japanese Government.

LearnLab – is originally funded by *the National Science Foundation*, and it leverages cognitive theory and computational modeling to identify the instructional conditions that lead to robust student learning. A regular contributor at *the Cognitive Factors Research Thrust* since 2020.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Conference Program Committee

ICLR 2022, WSDM 2022, NeurlPS 2021, AISTATS 2021, EC 2022.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

GEIL 2018~2019

May 2018 – *September* 2019

Takahiro Oda — curriculum vitæ

Organized Japan's largest *Policy Making Contest for college students*. Designed, arranged and facilitated discussions on issues such as health inequities, intercultural society, and Japan's nuclear waste problem.

JENESYS 2019~2020

February 2020, March 2021

A people-to-people exchange program between Japan and the Asia-Pacific region, sponsored by *the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan*. Contributed from designing the discussion on foreign workers' problem to facilitating it at *Japan-ASEAN Student Conference 2019 and 2020*.

LANGUAGES

Japanese(native), English(TOEFL iBT: 104)

REFERENCES

Available upon Request.

Last Updated: January 24, 2022